Got you!
What was that blood he spat out?
Poison?
What's this?
You're strong.
That's no fun.
Straw Doll Technique:
Resonance!
How many of them are there?
We should just keep going
like it's whack-a-mole, huh?
Yeah.
Keep going.
Keep exorcising them for me.
We'll crush every last one of them.
It likely won't retaliate.
You mean its main body
doesn't have much offense
since its technique covers a
wide area, even limited as it is?
I'm only saying it's likely.
All the things we were worried about—
its technique's range,
the number of victims, the barrier—
All of those are subtracting
from its main body.
We're lucky.
We'll be able to exorcise it quickly, then.
Which means... the real
problem comes afterward.
Kugisaki!
I'll be fine.
You just whack the mole.
Damn it!
She gets sucked away so often!
But what was that just now?
The mole?
That earlier one?
It's neither!
Kugisaki?
Oh, hey, it's my older brother!
Me, too!
It fled?!
Should I let it go?
Chase after it!
Kugisaki and that thing both
went outside the barrier!
She might be battling against something
more troublesome than we expected!
In contrast, things are far
easier here than anticipated!
I can handle this by myself!
Prioritize Kugisaki! Go after it!
If things get bad in here,
then you come out, too.
Why, you...
Don't touch me!
You're a woman?
Well, pardon me.
We brothers were tasked with an errand.
But killing jujutsu sorcerers
isn't part of that.
If you withdraw, we'll let you escape,
young lady.
An errand?
Hm? I presumed you were
on the same errand.
A cursed spirit? A curse user?
Which is he?
And what is that smell?
Last one!
Your sneak attack's too simple.
I told you, it's too simple.
Did I exorcise them all?
That takes care of Tsumiki for now.
Now to...
One survived?
That wasn't its main body just now?
The barrier hasn't collapsed, either.
What?
I shouldn't try too hard to find logic
in a cursed spirit's behavioral patterns,
but that fact had been
nagging me this whole time.
Why did it just start killing
humans it had marked now?
The first one was killed in June.
And in June...
Our objective here...
is to retrieve Sukuna's finger.
JUJUTSU KAISEN
Episode 23: The Origin of Blind Obedience - 2 -
Some have a presence
that's too overwhelming.
Some keep very quiet.
Some have already been
absorbed by a cursed spirit.
This is resonance.
Sukuna's finger kept its power repressed
within the cursed spirit
that had absorbed it,
but back in June,
when Sukuna manifested in Itadori,
it released its cursed energy.
It looks the same
as the one from the juvenile detention center,
but it's probably several degrees...
stronger!
Nue!
Okay, I win again.
This is unusual.
You rarely ask me to train you, Megumi.
Are you in a rush after Yuji surpassed you?
Well, beggars can't be choosers.
It bothers you that much to rely on me?
Megumi, listen.
I think you have just as much ability
and potential as Yuji does.
The problem is just your mindset.
Megumi,
you don't know how to
bring out your best, do you?
Huh?
Are you saying I haven't
been giving it my best?
I'm not saying you haven't.
I'm saying you can't.
For example, in the baseball game the other day...
Why did you go for a sacrifice bunt?
Did you want Nobara to advance the bases,
even if it meant you'd be out?
That's a splendid attitude,
but Yuji and I would
always go for a home run.
I'm not saying a bunt is bad.
Baseball is a team sport,
and everyone has their role to play.
But jujutsu sorcery is an individual sport.
Coordinating with other sorcerers
is important, isn't it?
Sure.
But no matter how many
allies you have around you,
when you die, you'll be alone.
You can only piece together
undervalued data on yourself and others.
You can't imagine a stronger
future version of yourself.
Maybe that's because of your trump card?
You believe that in the worst case,
you can resolve everything
at the cost of your life.
But at that point, forget about me.
You'll never even measure up to Nanami.
Dying to win and risking death to win...
are completely different, Megumi.
Give it your best.
Be greedier.
How many seconds was I unconscious?
My Demon Dog's destroyed...
no, the technique was released.
This is it for me.
Sacred treasure, swing...
What a waste of talent.
Screw it!
A jujutsu sorcerer's growth curve
isn't necessarily a gentle slope.
Back then, why did you run?
Spit out the entire depths of my shadow...
Worry about a specific structure later,
and just push it out as soon
as I collect the cursed energy.
Imagine a future version of myself
who's freely surpassed my limits!
I'll do it!
With a strong foundation,
and a little bit of sense and imagination,
it just takes the slightest trigger
to change a person.
Domain Expansion:
Chimera Shadow Garden!
It's incomplete!
It's ugly work at best.
But for now, that's fine!
Broaden it...
more freely!
The interpretation
of the technique!
Demon Dog Totality's claws
were able to injure that thing.
They'd have no trouble piercing through
you when you're caught off-guard.
I'm tired.
Now, where are those guys?
Good!
That's good!
JUJUTSU KAISEN
There's one fundamental rule
for interacting with others.
Do you know what that is?
I don't.
It's "I won't kill you,
so please don't kill me, either."
You can substitute "kill"
for anything you please.
The point is drawing a line where you agree
not to infringe on the other person.
In order for both people to exist together,
they need that rule.
Breaking that rule, swaggering about,
and having others trying not to anger you
must have felt real pleasant.
Next time you do it in
front of me, I'll kill you.
What did we ever do to you?
Figure it out yourself,
or go die.
Hey!
T-T-T-T-Today's the day I tell
off Ikezawa and his buddies!
I'm not their gofer anymore!
You can do it, Aida-shi!
But I might become their next target,
so don't try too hard, Aida-shi!
Hey, come on, fatty!
I'm changing the line!
I'll tell them this fatty is my
replacement starting today!
You'd sell your friend out, Aida-shi?!
Shut up!
Megumi.
Huh?
Isn't that Ikezawa and his
buddies piled up over there?
You said you wouldn't fight anymore.
Don't act like you're my guardian.
I hate bad people.
They act so damn superior when
their empathy and imagination
are as empty as a vacant lot.
I can't deal with good people.
They forgive those bad people.
Then they view the act of
forgiveness as a noble thing.
Makes me want to vomit.
Tsumiki's a model example of a good person.
You disgust me.
Oh, sorry.
I didn't think it'd spill out.
When I was in first grade,
my father and Tsumiki's mother,
one parent each, hooked up...
and then vanished without a trace.
A suspicious white-haired man told us...
You know, your dad...
He's from the Zen'in Clan,
a big clan among jujutsu sorcerers,
but they're such good-for-nothings,
it freaks even me out.
Your father left the clan to have you.
Megumi-kun,
your father was saving you as the ultimate
card to use against the Zen'in clan.
Pisses you off, doesn't it?
That solved the mystery of how
they got the funds to disappear.
Apparently, I had been sold
to that Zen'in clan.
Yeah, it pisses me off.
Especially your lack of tact about it.
Plus, that irritating man stopped
my sale to the Zen'in clan,
and used the promise that I would work
as a jujutsu sorcerer as collateral
to get financial aid from
Jujutsu High to support us both.
What's this jujutsu sorcerer crap, anyway?
It's bullshit.
Who the hell would I ever save?
Hey, Tsumiki!
What are you doing?
Megumi-kun, ciao!
Nothing.
Hey, hold on.
So did you give any thought
to the test of courage?
I don't want to go, but I'll go
because I'm worried about you.
Shortly after I started ninth grade,
Tsumiki was cursed.
The identity was unknown.
The origin was unknown.
But apparently there were several
victims of the same curse nationwide.
All I found out was that
nobody knew anything,
and Tsumiki was left bedridden.
If I have the time to curse someone,
I'd rather spend it thinking
about those precious to me.
She always smiled and spouted pretty ideals.
Not forgiving people isn't a bad thing.
That's just part of your kindness, isn't it?
She even accepted my disposition.
Yet Tsumiki would get genuinely
angry whenever I hurt someone, too.
That irritated me because
I thought it was hypocritical in light
of her leave-others-be policy,
but now I realize I had the wrong idea.
Just as I choose who I save,
she was choosing me to worry about.
I'm sorry.
I was just a kid.
I'll apologize.
So wake up already, stupid sister.
Damn, my head hurts...
This Yasohachi Bridge curse
was just overlapping the other one.
I doubt the curse that put Tsumiki
into a coma was undone.
Now, how do I break the news
about the finger... to... Itadori...
m 0 0 l 0 -150 l 98 -150 l 96 0
Fushiguro
Fell
Asleep
A huge presence suddenly appeared.
Did Sukuna's finger leave the barrier?
If a sorcerer exorcised the finger's host,
they're quite good.
But even if the finger's...
Even if the special-grade
cursed spirit was defeated,
they wouldn't come out unscathed.
I hope they're okay.
I misspoke.
Please forget what I just said.
Hold on!
He's going after the finger!
You think you can mock me
by running like that
and still get away from me?
I'm a bit insecure about my back, you see.
This is your warning.
If you see my back, I'll kill—
Oh, Kugisaki!
Oh, brother!
Y-Y-Y-You saw, didn't you?!
Huh?! Who?!
Sorry, brother!
Sorry, I guess?
It wasn't on purpose!
I'll kill you!
Then why are you dressed like that?
Is that the source of this weird smell?
Because it gets musty!
Rot Technique, Supreme Art: Wing King!
Death...
by Wasp!
Juju Stroll
Sensei!
Kugisaki!
Huh?
So annoying.
It's too hot for your craziness.
Fushiguro's getting hit on!
Formation B!
Roger!
Fushiguro-kyun!
Who is that woman?!
Have you forgotten the night
you toasted to my eyes?
Was it all a lie when you said your time
with me was the most enjoyable of all?!
That night! That night!
What?
Seriously, what?
Could you not touch him so casually, please,
you homewreckers?!
Megumi-chan has violin practice with me now.
Let's go home, Megumi-chan.
Today I'll have you master
"Twinkle Twinkle Little Star."
It's okay.
Don't mind them. Just go ahead.
The station's straight ahead.
Thank you so much.
Huh?
Okay, seriously, what is this?
Could you stop? You're embarrassing me.
Explain!
Ow!
Episode 24:
The Origin of Blind Obedience - 3 -